<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<section xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="programming-jupyter">
    <title>Jupyter Notebooks and CoCalc</title>
    <objectives>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p>
What kinds of technology are used by mathematicians and data scientists?
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
What is the structure of a Jupyter notebook, and how are Jupyter notebooks used in
mathematics and data science?
                </p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </objectives>

    <exploration>
        <statement>
            <p>
Throughout this course, you will complete the activities from this text within
Jupyter notebooks hosted on <url href="https://cocalc.com">CoCalc.com</url>, some
individually, and some within groups.
Your first activity is to set these Jupyter notebooks up for yourself!
            </p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>
First, either create an account at <url href="https://cocalc.com">CoCalc.com</url>,
or log in with the account provided by your instructor.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>
Go to <url href="#">TODO</url>, and use the <q>Open in CoCalc</q> button to create
a new project with your notebooks for the course.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>
Open the <c>Settings</c> for this project, and add your instructor's account as a
<c>Collaborator</c>. This allows them to see your work, and unlock the premium features
required for this course (such as importing data from other websites to analyze).
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>
Finally, navigate to the notebook associated with this activity. In the editable textbox
appearing below this activity in the notebook, double-click to edit, erase any default content,
and type the well-worn phrase of computing: <c>Hello World!</c>. Tap
<kbd>Shift</kbd>+<kbd>Enter</kbd> to save your note.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </statement>
    </exploration>
    <activity>
        <introduciton><p>(an activity that compares Python and SageMath kernels)</p></introduciton>
    </activity>
</section>

